本字幕由 PTT同志影视作品板 2013重新校稿
原字幕取自网路资源  仅供学习 禁用任何商业盈利行为
校稿： AAA、mohiwa
同志亦凡人 Queer As Folk S01E14
打电话给我的旅行社业务
Yeah, call my travel agent.
我要在巴哈马最好的度假村订一间房
Book me into the best resort in the Bahamas.
巴哈马?  为什麽?  南海滩去腻了吗?
The Bahamas? Why? Is South Beach over?
不  自由航空要我去回收那里的市场
No. Liberty air is sending me there for a marketing retreat.
所以这次是公事  不是去花天酒地?
Oh, so this is all work, no play?
对  我会参考一下
Oh, right. I'll just crack open
斯巴达指南  给你订房 (同志旅游指南)
the Spartacus guide.
嘿  你有空吗?
Hey, you got a minute?
有  我们只是在谈我的出差计划
Yeah, we're just planning my trip.
你最好先别讨论那件事
Well, you better hold off on that.
我会派达伦·强生代替你去
I'm sending Darren Johnson instead.
我希望你休息一阵子
I need for you to go home.
我先出去
If you'll just excuse me for a minute.
只是暂时的
This is just until
直到那件性骚扰事件平息为止
this whole harassment thing is over.
你难道不晓得「有证据才能定罪」吗?
Whatever happened to "innocent until proven guilty?"
自由航空那些人都很保守
Look, the Liberty Air folks are conservative.
如果他们发现你这个行销总监
What would they think if they found out
牵上一件同志性丑闻  他们会怎麽想?
that their account exec was involved in a gay sex scandal?
你是说  如果异性的丑闻他们就不在乎?
You mean they wouldn't mind a straight one?
我已经跟法务部门谈了
I've also spoken with legal.
你得跟人力资源部的代表面谈一下
You're going to be seeing a, uh, a rep from human resources,
还会有一场...
and there's going to be a...
法院那边的外部调查
outside investigation, followed by a tribunal
会派调解委员过来
with a... an impartial mediator.
那我的死期是什麽时候?
When's the hanging?
如果我是你  我会去请一位上好的律师
If I were you, I'd get myself a good lawyer.
我告诉过你不要上他
I told you not to fuck him.
你有注意到吗?
Have you ever noticed that when
你老妈没有来招呼我们的时候
your mom's not waiting on us,
我们餐点的份量大概少了三分之一
the portions shrink by approximately one third?
我点的不只是一根薯条  是一整份
I said "fries". Plural.
你有在听我说吗?
Are you even listening to me?
有  我不该上他的
Yeah, I shouldn't have fucked him.
这就像温斯福特跟我嘿咻
It's like Mr. Wertschafter fucking me.
他已经七十二岁了
Mr. Wertschafter's like 72!
你闭嘴行吗?  我想吃点东西
Do you mind? I was trying to eat.
你知道我是什麽意思
You know what I mean.
你不能"吃掉"你的属下
You don't prey on the help.
我没有"吃掉"他  是他先引诱我的
I didn't "prey" on him. He went after me.
我们去健身房吧
Let's go to the gym.
锻炼之後会感觉好点的
You'll feel better after you work out.
-你要来吗?    -我不去
-You coming?  -Oh, no.
我健身搭档不在  去健身房感觉不对
The gym isn't the same without my workout buddy.
我们可以做你的健身搭档
We'll be your workout buddies.
艾美特能让我放松一点
Emmett would let me get away with murder.
你们只会让我流汗紧张
You guys'll make me sweat.
那我们晚点在伍迪见喽?
So we'll see you at Woody's later on?
我的酒伴不在  伍迪也感觉不太一样
Ah, Woody's isn't the same without my beer buddy there,
他会对所有帅哥品头论足
Pointing out all the cute guys and...
还会洒我一身的酒
spilling drinks all over me.
我们也可以洒你一身酒
We'll spill drinks all over you.
你知道艾美特都是三分钟热度
You know Emmett can't commit to anything,
换男人  换护发产品
A guy, a new conditioner.
他会回来的  等着看吧
He'll get over this too. You'll see.
谢谢你的午餐
Thanks for lunch.
那天晚上
So, uh, there we were the other night,
吉姆和我坐在一起看比赛
Jim and I, sitting around watching the game.
我试着教他看懂美式足球
I'm... I'm trying to teach him football.
没错  你们受的了吗?
She is. Can you stand it?
我是不抱希望了
But I'm hopeless!
是啊  没错  但是那天
Yeah, you are. But anyway, so there I am,
我试着解释  什麽叫分数差
trying to explain point spreads yet again,
不知不觉中
When all of a sudden, uh,
我们互相注视着对方
We started to look into each other's eyes.
当我回神过来才发现  我们在接吻
The next thing I know, we were kissing.
唇舌纠缠  慾火焚身
With tongues and everything.
没错  你们受的了吗?
I know. Can you stand it?
现在  亲爱的  告诉他们
And now... Well, you tell them, honey.
我们订婚了
We're engaged.
你们受的了吗?  受的了吗?
Can you stand it? Can you stand it?
你们看到努力後的成果  多麽惊人吗?
Do you see the power of the work we're doing here?
别听信别人说什麽「这是不可能的」
Don't let anyone tell you that it isn't possible,
「你无药可救」
that you can't heal.
我想要听你们每个人
I want to hear success stories
你们成功的故事
from each and every one of you.
你们能做到的
You can do it.
你们一定行！  你们一定行！
You can do it. You can do it.
很振奋人心  是不是?
It's inspiring, isn't it?
看见别人改变了自己的命运
Seeing people change their lives.
是的  也给我们所有人希望
Yeah, it gives us all hope that...
相信有一天我们也能成功
One day we too can be a success story.
-我真希望我也能成功      -我也是
-God, I wish I was one.  -Oh, me too.
-我叫海瑟        -我是艾美特
-I'm Heather.    -Uh, Emmett.
-你好  -噢，好有力的握手
-Hi.   -Ow. Oh, nice, firm handshake.
对不起  我会改掉的
Sorry, I'm.... I'm working on that.
你是新来的吗?
Uh, so you're new here, huh?
对  大概来几个星期
Uh, yeah. A couple of weeks.
-你呢?  -六个月
- You?  - Uh, six months.
-有改善吗?  -还在努力中
- Has it helped?  - I'm getting there,
但是这是一场持久战
But it's a long road.
我第一次迷失是在大学的时候
You see, I first lost sight of the light back in college.
我跟我姐妹会的一个女生相恋了
I fell in love with one of my sorority sisters,
基妮
Jeannie.
在我父母的高尔夫俱乐部
I taught her how to play golf
我教她怎麽打高尔夫
at my parents' country club.
然後那天晚上  顺其自然的发生了
And then one night it just happened.
我们在第十八洞的草地上做爱
We made love on the 18th green.
天啊  我到现在还记得那个洞
God! oh, I still remember that hole.
但  她跟一个职业高尔夫选手订婚
But then, uh, she got engaged to a golf pro
然後搬去  北卡罗来纳州的派恩赫斯特
and moved to Pinehurst, North Carolina.
很遗憾
Sorry.
当她离开我的时候  我还以为我会死
When she left, I thought I would die.
我尝试跟不同的女人交往来忘记她
And I tried to get over it by going from woman to woman.
後来我开始问我自己   我怎麽会
And I started to wonder how I ended up
沉沦到如此地步
in such darkness.
从那时候开始 我想试图重回正常的生活
And that's when I started to find my way back to the light.
那你呢?
What about you?
我向上帝承诺过
I made a promise to god.
好酷啊
Oh, far out!
我是说  我真的相信他能听到我们的祷告
I mean, you know I... I really think he hears us, you know.
那你觉得
Uh, so, what do you say,
我们改天一起出去如何?
maybe you and me go out together some time?
你的意思是...
You mean, like o-on...
像约会那样吗?
on a date?
我不知道
I don't know. Uh...
你不是想成为一个成功的案例吗?
I thought you wanted to be a success story.
我真的很想
More than anything.
那我们就一起努力吧
Well then let's go for it.
明晚八点我来接你
Tomorrow night. I'll pick you up at 8:00.
-好  -好的
- All right.  - Okay
太棒了  但是...
It's great. But, um...
不是应该我去接你吗?
Aren't I supposed to pick you up?
对  好的
Yeah. Huh, right. Okay.
随便弄了些零食
Whipped you up a little snack.
所谓零食
"A little snack"
应该是一把"嘎吱船长"(喜瑞儿麦片)
is a handful of Captain Crunch.
家里刚好没有"嘎吱船长"了
I'm fresh out of Captain Crunch.
这是一点义大利面  番茄乾
This is a little penne, sun-dried tomato.
白酒奶油酱加上一些芝麻
That's a white wine cream sauce with arugula,
还有一些梅洛红酒
and a witty little Merlot.
好烫
Oh. It's hot!
我烫到舌头了
I burn... I...I burned my tongue.
我来帮你降温一下
Well let me cool it down for you.
最好不是我想的那个人
That better not be who I think it is.
是泰德
It's Ted.
我打扰到你了吗?
Hey, am I disturbing you?
我正躺在床上
So I'm lying in bed.
我正在看G片  太恐怖了
I'm watching this porno flick, right? It's terrible.
这两个男的竟然边做爱
These two guys are fucking and
边吃义大利面
eating pasta at the same time.
真有人会那样做吗?
Like anyone would really do that, right?
布莱恩刚才打给我
When Brian calls.
我觉得他快崩溃了
I think he's kind freaking out.
崩溃?
Freaking out?
对  他要我以一个会计师身份告诉他
Yeah. He wanted me to tell him, as his accountant,
他失业以後  他的存款还可以生活多久
how long he could go without a job.
那你怎麽说?
And what did you tell him?
像他那样花钱方式?  最多两个月
The way he spends? Two months, tops.
那他说什麽?
And what did he say?
他说非常感谢我
He thanked me very much
谢我一直以来当他的良师益友
for being such a wonderful and compassionate friend.
天啊  他真的是要崩溃了
Oh, my god, he is freaking out.
我晚点打给你
I'll call you later.
好的
All right.
怎麽了?
What's the matter?
是布莱恩  我得打电话给他
It's Brian. I've got to call him. Uh...
大卫  你不懂
David, you don't understand.
他要破产了  他要失业了
He's gonna go broke. He's gonna lose his job.
是你不懂
You don't understand.
我们不能拥有像茉蕾妮和琳赛
We're not going to have a relationship
那样的关系
like Melanie and Lindsay.
当然我们不能
Of course we're not.
我们又不是拉拉
We're not lesbians.
我的意思是
I mean...
在这个家里  我们的家里
There's only room in this...
我们的床上  我们生活里只能有
house, our house, our bed, our life,
我和你
for you and me,
而不是你和我  还有布莱恩
not for you and me and Brian.
我知道
I know.
答应我你不会让自己牵扯到
Promise me that you won't involve yourself
他的问题里  这是他自作自受
in his problems. He's made his own bed.
他可能因这件事被起诉
Now he can get sued in it.
我老实告诉你  你毁了我的生活
Let me get this straight. You fuck up my life,
你毁了我的爱情
you destroy my relationship,
现在你竟然还有种来找我
and now you have the astonishing, breathtaking gall
叫我当你的诉讼律师?
to ask me to represent you?
是的  我会付你钱的
Yeah. And I'll pay too.
收好你的钱  据我所知
Oh, keep your money, because from what I hear,
你可能很快会用到
You're going to need it.
好吧  恐同的美国公司再次获胜
Fine. Homophobic corporate America wins again.
拜托  就算你在办公室门口挂个牌子
Oh, please. You could hang a sign on your office door
写着「口交一次十分钱」
saying "blow jobs, 10 cents"
你还是可以
And you'd still have it better
过得比女人和非白种人好
than any woman or person of colour
你知道吗?  因为你是白人
because guess what? You're a white man.
在这个国家还是有点优势的
Which still counts for something in this country.
谢谢
Thanks.
好吧  让我开心一下
All right, just for laughs,
说说看关於这事  你的说词
give me your version of the story.
他想要  我就上了
He wanted it, I gave it to him.
不出所料  短而甜蜜
Like I asked for, short but sweet.
不是你想的那麽短
It wasn't that short.
那你这无私慷慨的举动  在哪发生的?
And where did this act of selfless generosity take place?
在我的办公室 还有我家
In my office and in my loft.
既然他之後还来找你上床
So he couldn't have minded it too
证明他根本不太在意  继续说
much if he came back for more. Go on.
然後他要我  帮他升职
Then he asked me to help him get a promotion.
你怎麽回答他?
What did you tell him?
我告诉他  他经验还不够
I told him he wasn't ready.
他怎麽回答?
How did he take it?
你说呢?
How do you think?
他觉得因为我们都是同志
He felt because we were both gay,
而且他跟我上床过了  所以理所当然
And we'd fucked, that somehow
他应该享有优先往上爬的权力
he was entitled to a free ride.
我没有答应
I didn't agree.
你一个月有多少炮友?
How many tricks do you have a month?
二三十个吧
20, 30.
天啊  多美妙的人生
Jesus, what a life.
我和多少人上床  跟这件事有关系吗?
What does the number of guys I do have to do with it?
唯一一次  你干过所有会动的生物
Well for once, the fact that you
这个才赋
screw everything that moves
证明了你的地位  也是你最佳的辩词
is your finest quality and your best defense.
因为你不需要为了想干一个人
You didn't have to abuse your position
而滥用你的职权
at work in order to get laid.
"打炮反辩"?
"the fuck defense"?
我们得证明他
We've got to prove that when this
没有得逞後
kid didn't get what he wanted,
他决定用法律诉讼进行报复
he decided to use the law in order to get even.
所以你会接这个案子吗?
Then you'll take the case?
听着  不是我想要救你才帮你
Look, not that I give a shit about saving your ass,
只是  让你後半辈子欠我份人情
But it might be amusing to have you indebted to me
也许还满有趣的
for the rest of your life.
跳吧
Do it.
-跳吧  -跳吧
- Do it. - Do it.
往前跳一大步
Do the hustle.
可以别这样吗?
Do you mind?
怎麽了?  小公主
What's the matter, princess?
我在做家庭作业
I'm trying to do my homework.
好吧  打扰了
Well, excuse us!
嘿  小迈
Hey, Mikey.
他们在干嘛?
What are they doing?
重温年轻时光
Reliving their youth.
跳个哈索舞
Do the hustle!
你们真的是怪咖一族
You people are so weird.
如果你不喜欢
Well, if you don't like it,
你为何不回你房间?
Why don't you just go up to your room?
让我重述一下  「我的房间」
Oh, let me rephrase that, "my room".
你能别纠结这事儿了吗?
Would you let it go, already?
是啊  小迈
Yeah, Mikey.
你现在可是医生娘
You're a doctor's wife now.
对啊
That's right.
想想我过去一直担心
And to think I used to worry
你会一辈子都跟在那个人的屁股後面
that you'd be spending your life
他叫什麽名字来着?
following after... What's his name?
你能不能  不提布莱恩?
Would you leave Brian out of this?
他已经有够多的麻烦要处理了
He's got enough shit to deal with.
什麽麻烦?
What kind of shit?
一个员工告他性骚扰
Some guy at work is suing him for sexual harassment.
这很严重  他可能会丢掉工作
It's really serious. He could lose everything.
我早知道  总有一天他会
I knew some day he'd stick his dick
被他的小弟弟所害
where it didn't belong.
我们应该做点什麽
Well, we've got to do something.
小阳光  我想你没有什麽可以帮他
Sunshine, I don't think there's anything you can do.
恐怕...
I'm afraid...
布莱恩最後搞了  他最不该搞的人...
Brian's fucked the last person he should have...
他自己
himself.
很抱歉  亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
你是他最好的朋友
You're his best friend.
你应该做点什麽的
You should do something.
我一定会帮他的  如果我能帮上忙的话
I...I would do something if I could.
管好你自己吧
J-just mind your own business.
请找卡麦伦医生
Dr. Cameron, please.
我是迈克
It's michael.
我知道我们今晚已经安排好了  但是
Listen, um, I I know we had plans tonight, but, uh,
我妈妈  她有点不舒服
My mom's got this... She's not feeling well.
她得了流感  感冒发烧又咳嗽的
She's got this flu-cough-fever-cold kind of a thing,
是啊  你知道的  所以我想...
Yeah, you know? And I thought I'd, you know,
陪在她身边照顾她
Stick around, and, uh, keep her company.
去你的
Fuck you.
听着  我只是想让你知道
Look, I-I just want you to know
-我对这件事感到很抱歉  -是喔?
- That I'm really sorry about this. - Really?
这可真让我好过些
That makes me feel a lot better.
我  我别无选择  如果...
Uh, I... I had no choice. If...
如果我不依你的要求做的话
if I didn't do what you wanted,
你会开除我
You'd have fired me.
不  你只是想帮人口交来获得升职
No, you just tried to get ahead by giving head,
顺带一提  你的技术还不怎麽样
Which, by the way, you're not very good at.
很明显地
We obviously
我们的记忆有很大的出入
remember things very differently.
是的
Yeah!
我记得发生什麽事
I remember what happened.
如果你不介意我的建议
If I could propose something...
我很乐意忘掉整件事  如果
I'd be more than willing to forget the whole thing if...
你跟我说你很抱歉  然後
you'll say you're sorry, and
重新考虑让我晋升
reconsider me for that position.
你知道吗  你还真是有提案的天分
You know, you have a real talent for propositions.
能不要站这麽近吗?
Would you mind not standing so close?
怎麽?
Why?
你担心会发生什麽事吗?
You worried something might happen?
像是我可能会用我的职权
Like I might use my position of power
来占你那紧实小菊花的便宜?
to take advantage of your tight little asshole?
天啊
God!
滚出我的办公室
Get out of my office.
在和你一起看「歌剧魅影」之前
You know, I never realized till seeing it with you
我从没想过这是一部壮烈的悲剧
that "a night at the opera" was such an epic tragedy.
很抱歉  只是去年万圣节
I'm sorry. It's just that last halloween,
琳赛扮演格罗克  而我扮演哈普
Lindsay went as Groucho and I went as Harpo.
怪不得你这麽激动
Well, that explains it.
哦  天啊
Oh god,
不是针对你  但我真希望她能陪我来看
Nothing personal, but I just wish she was here.
我能理解
I understand.
大部份和我约会的人  都希望
Most of my dates wish
他们是和其他人在一起
they were with someone else.
别那样说
Oh, don't say that.
-你是个理想的对象  -我知道
- You're a real catch. - I know.
我真走运  拉拉们都觉得我魅力无限
Just my luck, lesbians find me irresistible.
-不是吧  -怎麽了?
- Holy shit! - What?
我让你性奋了?
I got you all excited?
难以置信
I don't believe it.
泰德  茉
Ted. M...
茉蕾妮  你们好
Melanie, h-hi.
这是海瑟
Um, this is Heather.
我的约会对象
My date.
-抱歉  我以为你说她是...  -他说了
- I'm sorry, I thought you said... - He did.
我们要去吃披萨
We're going for pizza.
你们要一起来个双人约会吗?
You want to double?
-双人约会?  -对啊
- Double? - Yeah.
他们不是一对  海瑟
They're not really a couple, Heather.
-我是甲甲(男同)　-我是拉拉(女同)
-I'm a homo.　　 -And I'm a lesbo.
我刚才看你们拥抱还以为你们是正常人
I thought from the hug that maybe you were normal.
我们是正常人
We are.
你到底是怎麽了
What the hell's gotten into you?
他看到了那道光
He's seen the light.
那光照在哪里?  你的屁股上吗?
Where are they shining it? Up your ass?
"寻觅灵光"是帮我们建立一个...
"See the light" is helping us build a...
幸福的　异性恋生活
happy, heterosexual life.
当你建立那生活的时候
Yeah, well while you're at it,
为何不叫巫师先给你一个脑袋?
why don't you ask the wizard for a brain?
我很高兴我们可以博你一笑
I'm so glad that we amuse you.
谁高兴了?  我气炸了
Who's amused? I'm outraged!
无视她  海瑟  她无法理解
Just ignore her, heather, she doesn't understand.
我理解你这个混蛋
I understand you assholes
把同志权益运动倒退了50年
are setting back the gay rights movement about 50 years.
走吧  艾美特  我不太喜欢你的朋友
Come on, emmett, I don't think I care for your friends.
艾美特  等等
Emmett, wait.
至少我们能找个时间聚一聚吧?
Can we at least get together sometime?
当然可以  如果你想要...
Sure. Um, if you ever want to...
寻觅灵光
see the light...
来加入我们吧
Come to a meeting.
我想你应该有一点饿了
I thought you might be a little hungry.
一点?
A little?
你知道我们要是全吃光了会变成什麽吗?
Do you know what we'd turn into if we ate all that?
一对肉垮痴肥的同志
A couple of fat, flabby fags
而且我们再也找不到男人嘿咻了
who nobody would want to fuck, ever.
嘿  我们开动吧
Ah. Let's dig in.
你知道高中时哪件事让我记忆犹新吗?
Mmm, you know what I remember from high school?
是不是那次生物课上
The time in biology class
你射进一根试管里
when you beat off in a test tube
然後把试管当作业交出去这件事?
for your science project?
不是  是吃的
No. Food.
你家里总是有很多吃的
There was always lots of food at your house.
那是义大利传统
That's an Italian thing.
你家里总是有很多酒
And there was always plenty of booze at your house.
是啊
Yeah, huh?
那是爱尔兰传统
That's an Irish thing.
这是什麽?
What's this?
「省钱生活备忘录」
"Reality checklist"?
是的  我正在尝试把我的生活简化
Yeah, I've been thinking of simplifying my life.
「衣服?」
"Clothes"?
你的确能在衣服上省一大笔钱
You... You can certainly save money on clothes.
「护肤品?」
"Cosmetics"?
是啊  那些法国进口的抗老产品
Yeah, the french anti-aging shit
一支要100美元
Costs $100 a tube and...
我看起来还是不像19岁
I still don't look 19.
「出去玩」
"Going out"?
对啊
Yeah.
我觉得我每周少去一次夜店
I figured I could probably survive hitting the clubs
也能活下来
five times a week instead of six.
我可不确定  这真是很大的牺牲
I don't know. That's a pretty big sacrifice.
「阁楼?」
"Loft"?
嗯…
Yeah, well...
我没必要住在又大又贵的房子里，对吧？
What do I need this big, expensive place for, anyway?
这是你的家啊
This is your home.
也许事情还没到那个地步
Maybe it won't come to that.
如果真的那麽糟的话
Hmm. Well, if it does,
我就去找个甜心富老爹  像你那位医生
I'll just get a rich sugar daddy like the doc.
他才不是我的甜心富老爹
He's not my sugar daddy.
如果我不小心点  他可能就会离开我
If I'm not careful, he might not even be my boyfriend.
什麽?  天堂里也有烦心事?
What? Trouble in paradise?
他不知道我在这里
He doesn't know I'm here.
已经开始骗他了?
You're lying to him already?
他怕我把你从他身边抢走吗?
What is he afraid, I'll steal you away from him?
最後一支鸡腿
Last chicken leg.
你是专抓小鸡的老鹰
You're the chicken hawk.
他们是在诬陷我
I didn't do what they're saying.
我只是想让你知道
I just want you to know that.
你不需要解释
You don't have to explain.
嘿  你还记得吗?
Hey, you know what I remember?
高三的时候
Senior year
我们本来要加入一个乐队
we were going to be in a band.
你本来可成为下一个罗伯特·史密斯
You were going to be the next Robert Smith.
是啊  那个梦想很快就破灭了
Yeah, well, that dream died real fast.
那时我们超酷的
We were damn good.
你还留着那把吉他吗?
Hey, do you still have that guitar?
他们应该准许女人参赛的
You know, they ought to let women in this contest.
我可是胸怀大志的
I've got a great chest.
是啊  很大的胸
Yeah, chest of drawers.
嗨  大卫
Hey! David. Hi.
正说到「胸」怀大志呢
Speaking of great chests.
迈克没跟你一起?
Where's Michael?
在这里  他不在这里吗?
Here. He's here, isn't he?
我没见到他
I haven't seen him.
他打电话说你病了
Well, he called and said that you were sick.
他这麽说?
He did?
他还说他要在这里过夜
And he said he was spending the night here...
以便照顾你
To take care of you so...
所以我就带了鸡汤过来
I thought I'd bring over some chicken soup.
哦  你真好
Oh, that is so thoughtful.
正是医生的叮嘱
And just what the doctor ordered.
嘿  你就是医生
Hey, you're the doctor.
所以说  你没生病喽?
So you're not sick?
别这麽失望
Well, don't sound so disappointed.
她从1986年冬天开始嗓子就痒不停 (很吵之意)
She had a scratchy throat back in the winter of '86.
谢谢你
Thank you.
「你对我的爱」
Just because you love me
「不能剥夺我的自由」
doesn't mean I can't have my way
「我想离开」
Just because I'm leaving
「也是身不由己」
doesn't mean I don't want to stay
这些是他们在听证会要问你的
Okay, let's go over the questions
我们来演练一下
they're going to ask you at the hearing.
-现在吗  -哈  如果你不想让他们
- Now? 　-Huh! If you prefer,
把你踢出公司的话  最好就是现在
we can wait until they boot your butt out of the company.
哦　天啊  是你请我当辩护律师
Yes, now. Christ, you asked me to represent you...
好吧  我投降
Okay, fine.
开始吧  不过
Fire away. But...
温柔点
gently.
我说温柔点
I said gently.
贾斯汀  拜托一下
Justin, please?
对不起
Sorry.
把这个喝了  这是秘方调配的
Here, drink this. It's a secret recipe
我的酒鬼阿嫲过去常做这个
that my alcoholic grandmother used to make.
天啊  这闻起来像
Jesus! It smells like a...
穿过的球员内裤
dirty jockstrap.
这麽说来 你应该会喜欢
Well, in that case you should like it.
所谓秘方应该就是她尿在里面
The secret is she pissed in it.
我只是想帮你
I'm just trying to help you.
你知道我什麽都愿意为你做
You know I'd do anything.
天啊  我们祈祷法官也是同志
Oh, Jesus, let's just pray the arbitrator's gay,
而且觉得他很帅
and thinks he's cute.
对不起  我不知道你
I'm sorry, I didn't know you'd...
没关系的  我也不
It's okay, neither...
我也不知道
Neither did...
我过会儿再回来
I'll come back later.
不  别走  我只是在帮助布莱恩
No, stay. I... I was just helping Brian with...
我知道  他告诉我了
I know. He told me.
看看这是谁  宝贝
Look who's here, honey.
嗨  小伙子
Hey, buddy.
宝贝儿啊
Hey, sweetheart.
他想你了
He misses you.
我想
Look, um...
我看我们还是晚点再谈吧
Why don't we go over this later?
你别因为我而急着离开
You don't have to rush off because of me.
我得上班去了
I have to get to work.
能把这垃圾拿走吗
Would you get this shit away from me?
这是我祖母的秘方
It's my grandmother's recipe.
他已经醉了
He's majorly hung.
第一次
And for once,
他没在谈论我的大鵰
he's not talking about my cock.
别哭了  乖小伙儿
It's okay, sunnyboy,
你老爸会康复的
Your old man'll recover.
他不是因为你哭  他想念茉蕾妮了
He's not crying over you, he misses Melanie.
你刚刚不是有机会
Well, you just had your chance.
为什麽不求她回到你身边
Why didn't you beg her to come back?
你说什麽
Excuse me?
出轨的人是她
She's the one who cheated.
也许事出有因呢
Well, maybe she had reason.
现在你站在她那边  真是有趣极了
So, now you're taking her side? Huh, that's amusing,
这些年来 你一直都讨厌她  羞辱她
After all the years you spent hating her, humiliating her,
千方百计逼她离开我们之间
trying to force her out of our lives every chance you got.
恭喜你啊  你的目的达成了
Well, congratulations, you finally got what you wanted.
你说得对
Yeah, that's right,
都怪我吧
Blame me.
为什麽不？
Why not?
所有人都爱怪我头上
Everybody else does.
也许这正是你想要的结果
Well, maybe you finally got what you wanted.
听着
Look,
我得提前回去上班
I'm going to have to go back to work sooner than I thought,
所以我得找个保姆
which means I'll need a sitter.
我来吧  我和盖斯相处得很好
I'll do it. I'm great with gus.
我知道的  不过我需要一个全职保姆
Oh, I'm sure. Only I need someone full-time.
贾斯汀  帮我把支票簿拿来
Justin, will you get my cheque book?
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
我是说  你现在这个情况
I mean, with what's going on...
小事一椿
It's not a problem.
我说过我会照顾你和盖斯的
I said I'd look after you and Gus,
我不会食言的
and I am.
-谢谢你    -不客气
-Thanks. -Yeah.
什麽
What?
我知道我身上很难闻
I know I smell bad.
是伏特加的味道
It's Vodka.
出什麽事了
Something wrong?
没有  没事
No. Not at all.
只是  你能别再让那些大象
Except, could you keep the elephants
在楼梯上跑来跑去了吗
from running up and down the stairs?
你说什麽
Excuse me?
没事
Nothing.
你凌晨三点才回来
You got in 3 last night.
是吗
I did?
你妈妈一定病得很严重
Your mother must've been really sick.
你知道的  流感  咳嗽
Yeah, well you know those flu-cough...
受凉发烧之类的
Fever-cold kind of things?
迈克  我知道她没生病
Michael, I know she wasn't sick
我去她家找你了
'cause I went over there to find you.
-他妈的　　  　-然後呢
-Oh, shit.　 -And then...
我赶上了伍迪吧的夜场演出
I caught the late show at Woody's.
他祖妈的
Double shit.
你知道的  你和布莱恩合奏得挺好听
You know, you and Brian play pretty well together.
你们两个真是
The two of you... Well I...
当然　我还有什麽好惊讶的
Of course I shouldn't be surprised.
我跟你说过了
I told you, Brian's going through
布莱恩现在过得很痛苦
a really tough time right now.
是的  但我也跟你说过
Yeah, and I told you something too.
所以  如果事情要变成这样的话
So if this is the way it's going to be,
你对我撒谎  是为了去和他见面
You lying to me so that you can be with him...
我觉得要重新考虑我们之间了
I think we better rethink things.
你他妈的是怎麽回事？
What the fuck's the matter with you,
骗大卫说我病了
Lying to David, telling him I was sick?
我当时都无言以对
I didn't know what to say.
-无言？这可鲜了　　　  -闭嘴
-And that was a first.　 -Shut up.
好啦  我做错了
All right, I made a mistake.
你当然做错了　如果你还继续这样
You're damn right you did. And you keep this up,
会毁了你们的关系  听到没
You're going to blow it, you hear me?
我说我知道错了，行吗？
I already said I was wrong, okay?
如果你想折磨人的话
If you want to torture someone, go to
去马路对面的「ＳＭ」酒吧
the "S and M" bar across the street.
你们怎麽无精打采的
What's with you guys, anyway?
这里可是同志酒吧
This is supposed to be a gay bar, remember?
我昨晚看到艾美特和一个女人在一起
I saw Emmett last night, with this woman.
至少当时她是这麽介绍自已的
At least that's how she purported to represent herself.
他真的要变直男了
He really is going straight.
我们不也是
And so are we.
我们都直入地狱了   照他们的话来说
Straight to hell, according to them.
但他不知道
Yeah, but doesn't he know that every reputable
过去25年进行的各种知名心理学研究
psychological study done within the past 25 years
都明确说到人的性向
emphatically states that a person's sexual orientation
在6岁就确定了
is determined by age of six,
有时甚至出生前就确定了
Sometimes even before birth,
而且这是完全无法改变的
And it's completely unalterable?
你告诉他们啊  小阳光
You tell 'em, sunshine.
江山易改　本性难移
A leopard can't change his stripes.
同志也一样
Either can a queer.
但是
You know,
江湖险恶
it's a nasty world out there.
如果艾美特没有勇气做基佬
So, if Emmett hasn't got the guts to be gay,
要我说  去他娘的
then I say fuck him.
但他仍是我们的朋友
You know, he's still our friend.
我就是无法接受他要离开
I just can't let him go that easily.
来杯史多力加冰
Can I get a stoli on the rocks?
我以前没见过你吧
Haven't I seen you before?
这可是老梗
That's original.
然後我应该回答「不，我们没见过」
And the answer is, "No, I don't think so."
不  那晚在巴比伦
No. It was the other night, at Babylon.
我记得你
I remember you.
但我不记得你
Well, I don't remember you.
加班了  医生
Working late, doc?
有点文书工作要做
Catching up on some paperwork.
听说你有点小问题
So I hear you have a problem.
对头  我的屁股里有根刺
Yeah, I've got this pain in my ass.
也许是用力过度造成的
Maybe it's from over-exertion.
也许就是你造成的
Maybe it's you.
那我怎麽帮你缓解病情呢
So how can I help alleviate your condition?
你可以放了小迈
You can lay off Mikey.
我的处方是
Well, my prescription for that
管好你自己的事
would be for you to mind your own business.
他就是我的事
He is my business.
而且在你离开他之後　我还得去安慰他
And he's going to be my business, long after you're gone.
我哪都不会去
I'm not going anywhere.
而且  我听说你有办法脱身了
Although I did hear that you may be on your way out.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
每个人都知道
Practically everyone,
但这不关我们的事
although that's not our concern.
但你的伴侣不这样认为
Your better half thinks differently.
我要他别搅和进去
I told my "better half" to stay out of it.
别来见我吗？
By forbidding him to see me?
告诉你
You know,
这样你留不住他
That's not how you're going to keep him.
只会失去他
That's how you're going to lose him.
医生
You know, doc,
你真不赖
You are good.
我的疼痛
That pain I was having is...
不药而愈了
feeling better already.
有什麽感觉
Feel anything?
有点麻麻的刺痛感
A numb, tingling sensation.
但我发现是脚麻了
But, uh, then I realized my... leg's asleep.
你呢
How about you?
胃里有点恶心
Um, just a queasiness in my stomach,
就像吃了坏掉的蛤仔肉一样
like when you eat a bad clam.
我们不是非做不可的
Look, we... don't have to do this.
不  我想要一个完美的结局
No! I want a success story.
我也是
Oh, so do I.
也许我们
Uh, maybe if we, um...
也许我们可以幻想一下
maybe if we fantasized.
你幻想一个完美男人
You know, you... think about the perfect man,
我幻想一个完美的女人
and I'll think about the perfect woman.
精神上的辅助也许可以帮我们
It's a crutch, but... if it helps us walk...
怎麽样
Well?
继续
Keep trying.
然後
And?
我觉得我有点感觉了
I think I'm starting to feel something.
我也是
Me too.
又是你
Aw, it's you again.
你还真是执着
You don't give up, do you?
你想要我放弃吗
You want me to?
你真的见过我吗
Did you really see me before?
是的  你和那个布莱恩在一起
Sure. You were with that guy, Brian.
你怎麽认识他
How do you know him?
大家都认识他
Everyone knows Brian Kinney.
他是个大混蛋
He's a real asshole.
-是吗　　　-是的
- Oh, really? - Yeah.
他总是过来追你
He's always coming on to you,
装的真的喜欢你一样
acting like he likes you.
其实他只是想打一炮
Really all he cares about is getting laid.
你怎麽知道的
How do you know?
他伤过你的心吗
Did he break your heart?
当然没有
Fuck no!
我没信过他的鬼话
I'd never fall for his shit.
而且  他不是我的菜
Besides, he's not my type.
他是你菜的吗
Is he yours?
开什麽玩笑
Are you kidding?
那什麽样才是你的菜？
So what is your type?
你可以做到!  可以做到!
You can do it. You can do it.
你可以做到
You can do it!
你感觉怎麽样
So... how was it for you?
我不怎麽排斥
You know, I didn't hate it.
你呢
Oh? You?
没有我想的那麽令人恶心
It wasn't nearly as disgusting as I thought it would be.
幻想真的起作用了
The fantasies really helped.
是的
Yeah.
你想的是谁
Who'd you use?
《安娜与国王》的茱迪·福斯特
Jodie Foster, "Anna And The King".
你呢
Ah. You?
《杀戮时刻》的马修·麦康尼
Uh, Matthew Mcconaughey in "A Time To Kill".
可惜我们没用《接触未来》
Mmm. Too bad we didn't use "Contact",
要不我们就可以在同一部电影了
We could've been in the same movie.
是啊
Yeah.
我们有自己的成功范例了
Well, we... have our success story.
是啊
Yay us. Huh.
你个性感的小贱人
You're one hot little fucker.
你也很性感啊
You're pretty hot yourself.
哦～耶
Oh, yeah.
来啊　舔它
Go on, lick it.
就这样
That's it.
你比我上周遇到的男人好多了
You're hotter than the guy I had last week.
是吗
Is that so?
他要我穿着内裤　然後打我小屁屁
He wanted to put me in short pants and spank me.
我想要做的可不只这样
I want to do a lot more than that.
像什麽？
Like what?
不如直接做给你看
Like how about I show you?
不过你最好快点
Hey, you better hurry, though.
急什麽
What's the rush?
我午夜前回家
I've got a stupid curfew if you can believe it.
我父母的宵禁令
My parents want me home by midnight.
你...  还和父母住在一起？
You... live with your parents?
不然我还能住哪里？
Where else would I live?
我才17岁
I'm 17.
你17岁？
You're 17?
那你怎麽进酒吧的
So, how do you get into bars?
呃… 　假身份证啊
Duh! Like a fake I.D.
我不会告诉我爸爸的
I don't tell my dad though.
他会抓狂 发神经的
He goes totally psycho.
他发现我是同性恋之後　简直疯了
Like he did when he found out I was gay.
嗯…　你爸爸会抓狂？
Mmm, your... dad went psycho?
他抓着当时干我的男人
He went after the guy I was fucking at the time.
送到警察局去
Turned him in to the police.
警察局
Uh, the police?
判了10年
He'll be out in 10 years.
如果他知道我在这
If he knew I was here...
他怎麽会知道呢
Now, how would he know?
他不会知道的
Oh. There's no way.
除非我告诉他
Unless I told him.
但你不会说的  对吧
But you wouldn't do that, would you?
当然不会
Of course not.
我绝不会做这种事的
I would never do anything like that.
但是你得帮我个忙
Provided you do something for me.
记住  让我来谈
Remember, let me do the talking.
好的  这是你的强项
Yeah. You always do.
人力资源部调查员对你的提问
And when the investigator from H.R. asks you something,
-都得先和我商量再回答  -知道了
- confer with me first. - I got it.
不管结果怎麽样
Listen, however this plays out...
谢了
Thanks.
你本来没必要帮我的
You didn't have to help me.
你可以直接说「去你妈的」
You could have said "fuck you".
我知道
I know.
你在这儿啊  我在找你呢
Here you are, I was looking for you.
这位是
This is, uh...
莫蒂·瑞得  我老板
Morty Ryder, my boss.
这是茉蕾妮·马库斯  我的律师
This is Melanie Marcus, my attorney.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
自由航空扩充了一条
Look, Liberty Air was just awarded
到拉瓜迪亚的新航线
a new route into La Guardia.
主要是与东北部的企业合作
They're taking on the majors in the northeast.
-所以呢 　 -所以
- So?  　　- So,
他们想由你推销  打开国际市场
they want to go national with your campaign.
有很多事等着你做呢
You've got a lot of work to do.
那听证会呢
What about the hearing?
忘了听证会　控诉撤销了
Forget about the hearing. That matter's been dropped.
撤销了
Dropped?
怎麽回事
What happened?
我哪知道  而且谁在乎呢
Damned if I know, and who the hell cares?
5分钟後到我办公室来
Be in my office in five minutes.
真他妈的难以置信
Un-fucking-believable.
天啊  你是谁啊
Jesus! What are you,
特氟隆先生吗 (厕所清洁剂)
Mr.Teflon?
臭屎永远不会黏上身  (倒霉事不上身)
Shit just never sticks to you.
不知道怎麽  就像你和艾美特
I don't know how to... like, you or Emmett,
或许你想加入保龄球社团
But you might like to join a bowling league.
只限男性
Just the guys.
他在那儿
Oh, look, there he is.
或许这不是个好主意
You know, maybe this wasn't such a good idea.
我们出去吧
Let's just get out of here.
真是个惊喜啊
Well, this is a surprise.
欢迎来到「寻觅灵光」
Welcome to "see the light".
看这些人穿的衣服
The way some of these people dress,
他们应该改叫「驱除灵光」吧
they should change it to "turn off the light".
这是什麽意思？要强抢民女吗？
So what is this, like, an intervention?
你们要来绑架我
You're going to kidnap me and
然後把我丢进小货车的车箱？
throw me in the back of a van?
话说前头  我是不会上车的
I'll tell you right now, I'm not getting in any van.
没有什麽小货车
There's no van.
我连小货车都用不到吗？
I don't get a van?
我以为  至少也要租辆小货车
I think, at the very least, you could rent a van.
就只有我们两个，好吗？
Look, it's just us, Okay?
我们是来
And we came here to...
我不知道我们为什麽来这儿
I don't know why the fuck we're here but, you know...
艾美特  我们  试图跟你沟通
Emmett, we... We tried talking to you,
也试着跟你讲明道理
we tried reasoning with you.
我们甚至还叫了个G星
We sent a porn star.
-1000块啊　　   -好啦  算了吧
- $1,000.　　 　- It's Okay. Just let it go.
我知道
I know.
来吧  大家
Come on, everyone, let's, uh,
组成我们的灵光之圈吧
form our circle of light, hmm?
我们
We just...
我们想告诉你  我们还是爱你的
We wanted to let you know that we still love you.
也许没有上帝那麽爱你
Maybe not as much as Jesus,
但是
But...
也差不多了
Almost.
而且我们会想你的
And that we're going to miss you.
尤其想你跳舞的时候
Especially miss the way you dance
把手举过头顶的样子
with your hands over your head,
还有你的莉莎模仿秀  那是
and your Liza impersonation. That's...
我用来怀念你的方式
that's the way I'll always remember you.
谢了
Thanks.
我觉得上帝可没像你们这样欣赏我
I don't think God appreciates it quite as much as you do.
我觉得上帝比我们更欣赏你
Oh, I think God appreciates it even more...
因为祂是根据祂的形象创造你的
Because he created you in his image.
至少这是从小别人都是这麽教我的
At least that's what I was always taught.
因为上帝代表着爱
And since God is love and...
而且祂从不犯错
God doesn't make mistakes, then...
所以你的模样外表
you must be exactly...
一定就是祂希望你变成的样子
the way he wants you to be,
一定也是祂希望你能成变成的样子
the way he intended you to be.
不只是每一个人  甚至…
And that goes for every person, every...
每一个星球  每一座山
planet, every mountain, every...
每一粒沙  每一首歌
grain of sand, every song...
每一滴眼泪
every tear...
每一个屁精…
and every faggot.
我们都是祂的杰作   艾美特
We're all his, Emmett.
他爱我们每个人
He loves us all.
再见  小艾
Goodbye, Em.
我们要开始了噢
We're about to get started.
加入我们的灵光之圈吧
Come into our circle of light, hmm?
每次集会
We like to start every meeting
我们都会以一个成功的范例开场
with a success story.
而今晚  我觉得艾美特和海瑟
And tonight I just feel that Emmett and Heather
已经是成功的范例了  是不是
have a success story, don't you?
太棒了  讲来听听
Great! Let's hear it.
你得好好照顾这些东西  对吧
You've got to be careful with those, huh?
是的  这些都非常珍贵
Yeah, they're pretty valuable, so you
不能让它们见光
got to protect them from the light.
你肯定还在生我的气  对吧
Uh, you must be still mad at me, huh?
没有
No.
我不生气了
I'm not mad at you.
我想告诉你  我很抱歉  我撒谎了
Well, I want you to know that I'm sorry that I lied.
我也抱歉
I'm sorry too.
我  有时候
I... Sometimes I get, uh...
我想我是有点生
I guess I-I just get a little worked up
他的气
over, uh...
布莱恩
Brian?
Over Brian.
我几乎认识他一辈子了
I've known him practically my entire life.
我…  我不能就这样不见他
I... I can't just stop seeing him.
你没必要不见他
You shouldn't have to.
你可以随便去见任何你想见的人
You should feel free to see whoever you want to see.
毕竟  这是一段感情
After all, this is a relationship,
不是最高安全监狱
it's not a maximum security lock-up.
那麽你和布莱恩又重组乐队了
So you and Brian getting the band back together?
不了  我觉得後街男孩还
No, I don't think the Backstreet Boys
掩盖不了我们当年的风头
have usurped our former glory.
今晚你想出去吗
You want to go out tonight?
好啊
Well, sure.
那你去吧
You go.
-那你呢 　　　　　　　　   -我不去
- Well, what about you? 　-No.
我没什麽心情  我就呆在家吧
I'm not in the mood. I'll stay here.
你去玩  去跳舞
You go. You dance.
用你的魔鬼身材去
And you torture all those boys
折磨那些家伙吧
with your sculpted torso.
然後你回家  回到我身边
And then you come home to me.
我有个更好的主意
I think I have a better idea.
一杯马蒂尼  真是世界级美酒啊
A cosmopolitan. How cosmopolitan.
艾美特常说 「在匹兹堡里」
Emmett used to say, "in Pittsburgh,
「这些都是触手可及的」
It's as close as you can get."
我知道你有多想他
I know how much you're going to miss him.
事实上  你不懂
Actually, you don't...
但是  我感激你的感同身受
But, uh, I appreciate the sentiment.
跳支舞怎麽样
How about a dance?
不了  跳舞会让我想起他
Nah, it'd just remind me of him.
再来杯酒
Another drink?
我要开始哭了
I'd start to cry.
你的衣服掉了噢
You're losing your shirt.
-你还差点下课呢　　　  -是的
-You almost lost yours. -Ah, yeah.
我还是不知道他为什麽撤销了诉讼
I still have no idea why he dropped the suit.
是个迷嘛
It's a mystery.
我想  以後和别人做爱  要小心点了
I guess I'll just have to be more careful who I fuck.
你走运了    我明天就满18岁了
Lucky for you, I turn 18 tomorrow.
你生日想要什麽礼物
What do you want for your birthday?
一根漂亮、坚挺硬邦邦的大屌如何？
What about a nice, stiff dick?
你说起话来有点像他了
Now you're starting to sound like him.
我总记得  他以前常说
I'll always remember how he used to say,
「如果没有东西插进你的菊花」
"It's just not sex without...
「那不算是真的性交！」
without something up your butt."
你现在来巴比伦传教了吗？
Oh no, now you've come to Babylon to proselytize.
那不是我们来的目的
That's not why we're here.
我们已经看到了灵光
We've seen the light.
-我们知道     -我们知道
- We know! - We know!
不一样的灵光
A different light.
你们的成功范例怎麽样了
What about your success story?
我们成功了呀
Oh, we're a success story.
我们和小组分享了我们的故事
Oh? We shared it with the group.
我告诉了他们
I told them,
我们之中有些人喜欢舔阴道
some of us are meant to eat pussy,
有些人喜欢吮吸老二
and some of us are meant to suck cock.
但是不管怎麽样
But either way...
上帝是爱我们的
God loves us.
他们同意上帝是爱我们的
They agreed that God loves us.
然後他们要我们滚出去
And then they told us to get the fuck out.
你真的回来了？
Then you're really back?
宝贝  我的基情之火又复燃了
Honey, my flame has been rekindled,
而且比以前更耀眼
nd is burning brighter than ever.
抱歉
Oh! oh, sorry.
-抱歉  　-太好了
-Sorry.   -I'm not.
过来吧
Come on, you.
感觉到强大的同性节奏了吗？
Ah-h! Do you feel that gay thump-thump?
天啊  我怀念这儿！
God, I missed that!
a931952d32a14e5fbe1f227721b3dfe1